lightscribe.com 2006-12-19

# LightScribe - Privacy Policy

  |    space  space space

## E-mail Signup

Sign up to get the latest events, contests, news and more.

| 

PRIVACY POLICY

LIGHTSCRIBE RESPECTS YOUR PRIVACY

LightScribe technology was developed and patented by HP. A business unit of HP, LightScribe licenses its technology to optical industry leaders in drive and media manufacturing and to hardware, media and software brands.

LightScribe respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. LightScribe provides this Privacy Statement to inform you of our Privacy Policy and practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. We've structured our websites so that, in general, you can visit LightScribe on the web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. We make this notice readily available on our home page and at the bottom of every LightScribe web page.

  1. Sites covered by this Privacy Statement
  2. Types of information we collect
  3. Children's privacy
  4. How we use your information
  5. Who we share your information with
  6. Your choices
  7. Your privacy preferences and opting out
  8. Access to and accuracy of your information
  9. Keeping your information secure
  10. Changes to this Statement
  11. Contacting us

**1\. Sites covered by this Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement applies to the LightScribe website and domains.

**Links to non-LightScribe websites**  
The LightScribe website may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the LightScribe website. LightScribe does not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from LightScribe's. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. The personal data you choose to give to unrelated third parties is not covered by the LightScribe Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information. Some third-party companies may choose to share their personal data with LightScribe; that sharing is governed by that third-party company's privacy policy. 

**2\. Types of information we collect**

This Privacy Statement covers personal information, non-personal data collection and aggregate reporting.

  * **Personal information**  
Personal information is the information that is associated with your name or personal identity. LightScribe uses personal information to understand better your needs and interests and to provide you with better service. Once you choose to provide us with personal information, you can be assured it will be used only to support your customer relationship with LightScribe. We take seriously the trust you place in us. LightScribe will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others.

On the LightScribe website, you can request information, subscribe to marketing or support materials, or register yourself. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, and contact preferences.

To personalize our websites, services or communications and improve our products and services, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, and experiences with our products or services. Providing this additional information is optional.

  * **Non-personal information**  
Non-personal information is data about usage and service operation that is not associated with a specific personal identity.  

  * **Cookies**  
LightScribe.com web pages use cookies. These cookies are removed when the web session is closed. A “cookie” is a small data file transferred by a website to your computer's hard drive. LightScribe sends cookies when you surf our site, make purchases, request or personalize information, or register yourself for certain services. Accepting the cookies used on our site does not give us access to your personal information. Cookies are typically classified as either “session” cookies or “permanent” cookies. LightScribe only uses session cookies.

Session cookies do not stay on your computer after you leave our website or close your browser. The aggregate information collected permits us to analyze traffic patterns on our site. This can enable us over time to provide a better experience on our site by improving content or personalization and making our site easier to use.

Permanent cookies are those that remain on your computer. They are used to facilitate shopping, personalization and registration services. For example, cookies can keep track of what you have selected to purchase as you continue to shop and allow you to enter your password only once on Web pages where a login is required. Permanent cookies can be manually removed by the user. LightScribe.com does not use permanent cookies.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies by default, but you can usually refuse cookies or selectively accept certain cookies by adjusting the preferences in your browser. If you turn off cookies, there may be some features of our site that will not be available to you and some Web pages may not display properly. You can find information on popular browsers and how to adjust your cookie preferences at the following websites:

    *     *   * **Web Beacons**  
Some LightScribe.com Web pages and HTML-formatted e-mail newsletters use Web beacons in conjunction with cookies to compile aggregate statistics about website usage. A Web beacon is an electronic image, called a single-pixel (1x1) or clear GIF. Web beacons can recognize certain types of information on a visitor's computer, such as a visitor's cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page where the Web beacon is placed. You may render some Web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies. 

**3\. Children's privacy**

LightScribe is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. LightScribe does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and LightScribe does not target its websites to children under 13.

**4\. How we use your information**

LightScribe uses your personal information to provide you with services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we use your information to communicate with you, to provide service and support, and to update you on services and benefits. Occasionally we may also use your information to contact you for market research regarding LightScribe products or services. We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding such communications (see section 7, "Your privacy preferences and opting out").

Personal data collected online may also be combined with information you provide LightScribe through other sources such as product registration, call centers or public events such as trade shows or seminars.

Personal data given to LightScribe may be transferred across state and country borders for the purposes of data consolidation, storage and simplified customer information management.

Non-personal data is aggregated for reporting about LightScribe website usability, performance and effectiveness. It is used to improve the customer experience, usability and site content.

**5\. Who we share your information with**

LightScribe will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. LightScribe will not share your personal information with third parties except in responding to your requests for products or services. Your permission will be requested when you submit your information. LightScribe shares customer information across LightScribe-owned business entities and companies working on our behalf, but only as described above in "How we use your information."

LightScribe contracts with third-party service providers and suppliers to deliver complete products, services and customer solutions described in "How we use your information." Suppliers and service providers are required to keep confidential the information received on behalf of LightScribe and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for LightScribe. These service providers may change or we may contract with additional service providers to better accommodate our customers. LightScribe will not share personal information with any other third parties without your permission, unless required by law enforcement action, subpoena, or local law.

LightScribe or its related entities could merge with or be acquired by another business entity or some or all of their respective assets could be acquired. If such a combination or acquisition occurs, LightScribe will make every reasonable effort to notify you in the event we share with the merging or acquiring entity some or all of your personal information to continue serving you.

**6\. Your choices**

LightScribe gives you the choice of receiving a variety of information that complements our products and services. You can subscribe to receive certain product- and service-specific information and LightScribe-wide marketing communications. LightScribe-wide communications may include new product information, special offers, or an invitation to participate in market research. We give you a choice regarding delivery of LightScribe-wide communications by postal mail, e-mail and telephone. You can make or change your choices at the data collection point. Please refer to section 7 for further instructions. We will make every effort to honor your preferences. This option does not apply to communications for the purpose of administering order completion, contracts, support, product safety warnings or driver updates.

**7\. Your privacy preferences and opting out**  
**Non-subscription services**

LightScribe will not use your personal information for a different purpose than the one stated when you provided your data. Examples of unrelated uses include sending communications about special offers, product information, and marketing messages. You can, however, choose to receive these types of non-subscription communications by following the instructions below.

Please specify your privacy preferences by writing to our [Privacy Office](http://welcome.hp.com/country/us/en/privacy/privacy_contact.html) \- be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address in all correspondence.

**Subscription services**

To opt-out of receiving communications you have expressly requested (such as e-mail newsletters, software updates, etc.), use any of the following methods:

  * Select the e-mail "opt-out" or "unsubscribe" link, or follow the opt-out instructions included in each subscription communication.
  * Return to the web page(s) where you originally registered your preferences and follow the opt-out instructions
  * Write to the Privacy Office - be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address, and relevant information about your LightScribe subscriptions and registrations

**8\. Access to and accuracy of your information**

LightScribe strives to keep your personal information accurate. We have implemented technology, management processes and policies to maintain customer data accuracy. We will provide you with access to your information, including making reasonable effort to provide you with online access and the opportunity to change your information. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. Certain areas of LightScribe's websites may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords and other personal identifiers.

The most effective way to view and change your personal information is to return to the web page where you originally submitted your data and follow the instructions on that web page.

**9\. Keeping your information secure**

LightScribe is committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, LightScribe has in place appropriate physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect.

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. SSL encryption is designed to make the information unreadable by anyone but us. This security measure is working when you see either the symbol of an unbroken key or closed lock (depending on your browser) on the bottom of your browser window.

**10\. Changes to this Statement**

If there are updates to the terms of LightScribe's Online Privacy Statement, we will post those changes and update the revision date in this document, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. For material changes to this Statement, LightScribe will provide notification to affected customers.

**11\. Contacting us**

We value your opinions. If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please send them to the [Privacy Office](http://welcome.hp.com/country/us/en/privacy/privacy_contact.html).

_Rev. April 2006_

1A URL (Uniform Resource Locator) is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. For example, http://www.HP.com is the URL for HP's U.S. home page.  
2An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (TCP/IP) network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web, allowing web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet, browse and shop.

|
